CHASE JOHNSTON

EMAIL: chasej@live.com | PHONE: 603-703-4749 | LOCATION: Brookline, NH 03033 | GITHUB: https://github.com/johnstoc13 | LINKEDIN: www.linkedin.com/in/chase-johnston8

PORTFOLIO: https://johnstoc13.gihub.io/Updated-Portfolio/

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Website designer with a background in business management and experience creating modern, responsive websites for small businesses and leading positive change for teenagers and young adults. Extensive experience in multitasking, teamwork, communication and problem solving in a fast paced learning environment as an air traffic controller. Proven success repeatedly with accomplishments in experience, efficiency and teamwork.

TECHNICAL SKILLS & ABILITIES

LANGUAGES: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, ¡Query, Node, Inquirer, Express, Handlebars, Typescript

DATABASES: MySQL, Sequelize, MongoDB, Mongoose

TOOLS: Git, Heroku, Command Line, Bootstrap, Foundation, Moment.js, Auth0, Passport, File Stack, Microsoft Word, Excel, Wordpress, MadCap Flare, React, Angular

·

APPLICATIONS

SAFE SPACE

https://github.com/johnstoc13/safe-space | https://safe-space-ne.herokuapp.com/

- Front end developer for an application that offers a unique platform to help the LGBTQ community safely expand their orbit by connecting team members with resources, businesses and community.
- Angular, Material IO, Typescript, SCSS, Nest JS, Auth0, MongoDB, RXJS, Socket.IO, Heroku

TEAM BUILDER

https://github.com/johnstoc13/the-team-builders | https://the-team-builder.herokuapp.com/

- Front end design developer for a team-building app geared towards a remote workforce. Application was created to help build teams, foster creativity, and strengthen culture in just 2 weeks!
- Bootstrap, ¡Query, Handlebars, Auth0, File Stack, Passport, mySQL, Sequelize, Heroku

FLICK THE DECK

https://github.com/johnstoc13/Flick-the-Deck | https://johnstoc13.github.io/Flick-the-Deck/

- Flick The Deck is a fun application that combines "luck of the draw" with a faster path to movie selection based on user-selected criteria. Application is the result of a highly dynamic and cooperative team effort. Tasked with the front end design, ensuring mobile responsiveness using Foundation CSS.
- HTML, CSS, jQuery, Foundation, external APIs, Animate.css

WORK EXPERIENCE

ROBERT HALF - MANCHESTER, NH CONTRACTOR

JANUARY 2021 - PRESENT

- Successfully completed documentation translation project, including screenshots and doc review.
 - Complete staging and posting of driver files to two platforms.
 - Perform peer reviews of documents, processes, help files, and more..
 - Oversee documentation for other separate projects.

GRANITE STATE STUDIO, LLC – BROOKLINE, NH OWNER

MAY 2020 - PRESENT

- Creating fast, affordable, and responsive websites for small businesses.
- Oversee marketing, social media, and all other small business duties.

CHANGEMAKER TEENS, LLC - BROOKLINE, NH BUSINESS MANAGER

JULY 2017 - APRIL 2021

Co-owner and Business Manager for Changemaker Teens dedicated to helping teens and young adults discover a life direction that will bring purpose and meaning to their adult lives.

- Manage website, graphic design, sales and marketing strategies, and financial analysis.
- Negotiated enrollment into the Finger Lakes Area Community Endowment (FLACE) to operate as a 501c3 non-profit, ensuring maximum potential to improve the lives of teens throughout their community and nationwide.

FEDERAL AVIATION ADMINISTRATION - NASHUA, NH

SEPT 2008 - PRESENT

TRAFFIC MANAGEMENT COORDINATOR

- Radar controller responsible for the safe, orderly, and expeditious flow of traffic in one of the most congested and complicated airspace structures within the National Airspace System.
- Manage airspace constraints through traffic management initiatives, ensuring demand never exceeds capacity. Fluent in several computer technologies and platforms used in traffic management.
- Skills showcased at a Senior Leadership Conference within the FAA as a demonstration of professionalism and safety.
- Certified On the Job Training Instructor responsible for training new hires.
- Certified Controller In Charge to run operational areas when assigned.
- Selected to become a Professional Standards Representative in 2017.
- Capable of handling a very high stress environment that allows for zero mistakes.

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY OF NEW HAMPSHIRE - CERTIFICATE IN FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPMENT - 2020
MINNEAPOLIS COMMUNITY & TECHNICAL COLLEGE - A.A.S. AIR TRAFFIC CONTROL - 2007
METROPOLITAN STATE UNIVERSITY OF DENVER - B.S. AVIATION TECHNOLOGY - 2006